Debonair. Defiant. Defrosted.
Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery is a science
fiction, comedy, crime film directed by Jay Roach.
As a swinging fashion photographer by day and a groovy British superagent
by night, Austin Powers is the '60s' most shagadelic spy.
But can he stop megalomaniac Dr.
Evil after the bald villain freezes himself and unthaws in the '90s?
With the help of sexy sidekick Vanessa Kensington, he just might.
Austin Powers / Dr. Evil, played by Mike Myers.
Vanessa Kensington, played by Elizabeth Hurley.
Basil Exposition, played by Michael York.
Mrs. Kensington, played by Mimi Rogers.
Number Two, played by Robert Wagner.
Scott Evil, played by Seth Green.
Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery (or simply Austin Powers) is
a 1997 American spy comedy film directed by Jay Roach.
It is the first installment in the Austin Powers series.
It stars franchise co-producer and writer Mike Myers, playing
the roles of Austin Powers and his arch enemy Dr.
Supporting roles are played by Elizabeth Hurley, Robert
Wagner, Seth Green, and Michael York.
The film is a parody of the James Bond films and other popular culture from the 1960s, centering on a flamboyant, promiscuous secret agent and a
criminal mastermind arch-nemesis, who go into and come out of cryostasis at the same time as each other as their conflict spans decades.
The film, which cost $16.5 million to produce, was released on May 2, 1997.
It received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed $67 million worldwide.
It is now regarded as one of the best comedy films of all time, ranking
42nd on Bravo's "100 Funniest Movies of All Time" list.
The film spawned two sequels, Austin Powers: The Spy Who Shagged
Me (1999) and Austin Powers in Goldmember (2002).
In the years following Austin Powers in Goldmember, Myers has discussed the possibility of
a fourth film, though as of 2026 nothing official has come to fruition.
The film explores themes of undercover, missile,
spy, group therapy, secret agent.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.